Saskia Nowicki

Research Associate, Environmental Systems Science for Policy
Geography and the Environment · University of Oxford · S Parks Road OX1 3QY, UK

saskia.nowicki@ouce.ox.ac.uk +44 7464 753326 saskia-nowicki.github.io

Overview

Social-environmental systems specialist, leading transdisciplinary work on intersecting water quality, environmental hygiene, and health risks. Using systems frameworks and tools to improve understanding of human-environment interactions and identify leverage points to advance health equity through resilient safe water services. A decade of research and consulting experience in WASH and water management, engaging across scales, from molecular methods to hierarchical institutional dynamics. Recently seconded to the UK government to work on systems-based strategy for advancing environmental health governance.

Employment

Smith School of Enterprise and the Environment, University of Oxford	Oxford, UK
Postdoctoral researcher	Jun 2021 - present
Research assistant	2016 - 18 (2 years)
School of Geography and the Environment, University of Oxford	Oxford, UK
Casual lecturer	Sep 2021 - present
Teaching assistant	2018 - 21 (3 years)
Chief Brewer (Park Royal)	1935-1937
Researcher (Dublin)	1899-1935

Education

New College, Oxford University, B.A. Chemistry

1899

Research Projects

Publications

Books

Pearson, E.S. and John Wishart (eds.). 1943. "Student's" Collected Papers London: Biometrika Office.

JOURNAL ARTICLES

Student. 1938. "Comparison between Balanced and Random Arrangements on Field Plots." *Biometrika* 29(3-4): 363–378.

Student. 1936. "Co-operation in Large Scale Experiments." Supplement to Journal of the Royal Statistical Society 3(2): 115–136.

Student. 1931. "On the z Test." Biometrika 23(3-4): 407-408.

Student. 1931. "The Lanarkshire Milk Experiment." Biometrika 23(3-4): 398–406.

Student. 1929. "Statistics in Biological Research." Nature 124: 93

Student. 1927. "Errors of Routine Analysis." Biometrika 19(1-2): 151–164.

Student. 1926. "Mathematics and Agronomy." Journal of the American Society of Agronomy 18.

Student. 1925. "New Tables for Testing the Significance of Observations." Metron 5(3): 105–108.

Student. 1923. "On Testing Varieties of Cereals." Biometrika 15(3-4): 271–293.

Student. 1921. "An Experimental Determination of the Probable Error of Dr. Spearman's Correlation Co-efficient" *Biometrika* 13(2-3): 263–282.

Student. 1917. "Tables for Estimating the Probability That the Given Mean of a Unique Sample of Observations Lies between $-\infty$ and Any Given Distance of the Mean of the Population from Which the Sample Is Drawn." Biometrika 11(4): 414–417.

Student. 1909. "The Distribution of the Means of Samples Which Are Not Drawn at Random." Biometrika 7(1-2): 210–214.

Student. 1908. "Probable Error of a Correlation Coefficient." Biometrika 6(2-3): 302–310.

Student. 1908. "The Probable Error of a Mean." Biometrika 6(1): 1–25.

Student. 1907. "On the Error of Counting with a Haemacytometer." Biometrika 5(3): 351–360.

OTHER PUBLICATIONS

Student. 1905. "The Pearson Co-efficient of Correlation." Supplement to Report of 1904, Arthur Guinness Son & Company.

Student. 1904. "The Application of the 'Law of Error' to the Work of the Brewery." Report, Arthur Guinness Son & Company.

References

Available upon request, though likely would include Karl Pearson and Ronald A. Fisher. Please send corrections, feedback, or details of missed publications (of which there are probably a few) to steven.miller@ekohist.su.se